<!DOCTYPE html>
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en">

<head>
	<title>Description | Stay Fit 24-hour Fitness Club</title>
	<link href="styles/style.css" rel="stylesheet" />
	<meta charset="utf-8" />
	<meta name="description" content="Description" />
	<meta name="keywords" content="Fitness Club, Gymnastic, Swimming, Yoga, Description" />
	<meta name="author" content="Sharmik" />
	<meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0"></meta>
</head>

<body>
	<header>
		<h1><a href="index.html"><img src="images/fitness_logo.png" alt="Stay Fit Logo"></img></a> Stay Fit <em>24-hour Fitness Club</em></h1>
		<h5>COS60004 - Creating Web Applications</h5><hr />
	</header>

	<nav><h4>
		<a href="index.html">Home</a> |
		<a href="product.html">Description</a> |
		<a href="enquire.html">Enquire</a> |
		<a href="about.html">About</a> |
		<a href="enhancement.html">Enhancement</a>
	</h4></nav>
	
	<h1>Stay Fit <em>24-hour Fitness Club</em></h1>
	<h2>Why Excercise is important?</h2>
	<p>Exercising regularly, every day if possible, is the single most important thing you can do for your health. In the short term, exercise helps to control appetite, boost mood, and improve sleep. In the long term, it reduces the risk of heart disease, stroke, diabetes, dementia, depression, and many cancers. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommend the following:</p>
	<table id="recommendation">
		<!-- <caption>Recommendation</caption> -->
		<thead><tr>
			<th>For adults of all ages</th>
			<th>For pregnant women</th>
			<th>For children</th>
		</tr></thead>
		<tbody><tr>
			<td><ol><li>At least 150 minutes of moderate aerobic exercise like brisk walking or 75 minutes of rigorous exercise like running (or an equivalent mix of both) every week.  It’s fine to break up exercise into smaller sessions as long as each one lasts at least 10 minutes.</li><li>Strength-training that works all major muscle groups—legs, hips, back, abdomen, chest, shoulders, and arms—at least two days a week.  Strength training may involve lifting weights, using resistance bands, or exercises like push-ups and sit-ups, in which your body weight furnishes the resistance.</li></ol></td>
			<td>The guidelines for aerobic exercise are considered safe for most pregnant women. The CDC makes no recommendation for strength training. It’s a good idea to review your exercise plan with your doctor.</td>
			<td>At least 60 minutes of physical activity a day, most of which should be devoted to aerobic exercise. Children should do vigorous exercise and strength training, such as push-ups or gymnastics, on at least three days every week.</td>
		</tr></tbody>
		<!-- ref: https://www.health.harvard.edu/topics/exercise-and-fitness -->
	</table>
	<article>
	<h2>Facilities and detils</h2>
		<section>
			<div class="product_details" id="gymnastics"><h3>1. Gymnastics</h3> 
			<!-- ref: https://www.britannica.com/sports/gymnastics -->
			
			<p><strong>Gymnastics</strong>, the performance of systematic exercises—often with the use of rings, bars, and other apparatus—either as a competitive sport or to improve strength, agility, coordination, and physical conditioning.</p>
			<h4>Benefits of Gymnastics:</h4>
			<ul>
				<li>Gymnastics is an anaerobic sport.</li>
				<li>Gymnasts are among the strongest, pound for pound, of all the Olympic athletes. </li>
				<li>Gymnasts are among the most flexible of all athletes.</li>
				<li>Gymnasts are very good at both static and dynamic balance. </li>
				<li>Gymnasts learn early to fall without injuring themselves</li>
				<li>Gymnasts are among the smallest and lightest of athletes</li>
				<li>Gymnastics is a reasonably safe sport.</li>
			</ul>
			<a href="https://usagym.org/pages/home/publications/technique/1999/3/whygymnastics.pdf">Read more... ></a></div>
			<aside><img src="images/gymnastic1.png" title="Gymnastics File size: 4.30KB" alt="Gymnastics" id="gymnastics_img"></img></aside>
		</section>

		<section>
			<div class="product_details" id="swimming"><h3>2. Swimming</h3>
			<p>You don’t have to be an Olympian to enjoy the benefits of swimming. It is an effective way to improve and maintain your fitness and health regardless of your age or fitness level.</p>
			<h4>Benefits of Swimming:</h4>
			<ul>
				<li>Improvements in core strength and stability</li>
				<li>Improvements in the cardiopulmonary system (aerobic fitness)</li>
				<li>Improvements in HDL, or the good form of cholesterol</li>
				<li>Decrease in triglycerides</li>
				<li>Decrease in blood pressur</li>
				<li>Decrease in total cholesterol</li>
				<li>Improvements in skeletal muscle mass equaling improvements in strength, muscle tone, and power.</li>
			</ul>
			<a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.com/ornish-living/swimming-benefits_b_8051398.html">Read more... ></a></div>
			<aside><img src="images/swimming1.png" title="Swimming File size: 25.5KB" alt="Swimming" id="swimming_img"></img></aside>
		</section>

		<section>
			<div class="product_details" id="yoga"><h3>3. Yoga</h3>
			<p>Yoga's philosophy is based on eight limbs; only one of them, asana, is about the poses. The rest: yama, niyama, pranayama, pratyahara, dharana, dhyana and samadhi, are best described as moral and ethical codes to live by.</p>
			<h4>Benefits of Yoga:</h4>
			<ul>
				<li>It increases endurance, strength, and flexibility.</li>
				<li>Mental endurance and physical stamina are tested through holding postures for extended breaths.</li>
				<li>Arm and shoulder strength is increased as you use your own body weight for resistance.</li>
				<li>Lats, traps, and other back muscles begin to support the spine better than before.</li>
				<li>Abdominals and obliques are refined and toned through building core muscles.</li>
				<li>Posture begins to correct itself over time.</li>
				<li>Hip flexors are stretched and strengthened.</li>
				<li>Glutes, quads, hamstrings, and calves are strengthened.</li>
			</ul>
			<a href="https://www.gaiam.com/blogs/discover/the-benefits-of-yoga">Read more.. ></a><br /><br /></div>
			<aside><img src="images/yoga1.png" title="Yoga File size: 4.09KB" alt="Yoga" id="yoga_img"></img></aside>
		</section>
	</article>
	
	<footer><hr />
		&#169; <a href="http://www.swinburne.edu.au"><u>Swinburne University of Technology</u>.</a>&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Mark up by: <a href="mailto:101980352@swin.edu.au"><u>Sharmik</u></a>
	</footer>
</body>
</html>